

jhearn@gmail.com | 541.870.9000 linkedin: johndhearn | github: johnthebastard

PROFILE

Experienced iOS developer, mathematician, and former commercial fisherman. I write clean, efficient, maintainable code with the goal of building apps that are accessible to everyone. I thrive when I'm working with talented people to solve hard problems.

EXPERIENCE

iPHONE APP | Tomorrow 2017-2018 | Seattle, WA

- Developed, from infancy to maturity, award-winning financial planning app.
- Conceptualized with VP of Product the design of custom UI to collect and present detailed financial information in a way that was easy for users to understand.
- On-boarded and trained new engineers in use of Re and ReactiveSwift to manage app state and asynchronous data flow.
- Performed daily code reviews to improve team coding standards and app performance.
- Researched and implemented numerous libraries and frameworks for use in app to quickly reach minimum viable product.
- Developed a traffic control algorithm to delay UI updates until complete, interdependent data sets had been returned by the API.
- Developed and maintained client-side business logic to determine when users had completed legally necessary tasks to generate legal documents, and to guide them through unfinished tasks.
- Coded test suite to validate data models and business logic with Quick and Nimble.
- Wrote and maintained internal documentation for build pipeline tools, including Carthage, Cocoapods, ReSwift, custom build scripts, BuddyBuild (for continuous integration testing and test build deployment), and iTunesConnect.
- Migrated project dependency management from Cocoapods to Carthage to improve Swift build times.

BACKEND WEB DEVELOPMENT | John Hearn Consulting 2007 - 2016 | Portland, OR and Seattle, WA

 Worked with many clients to develop, test, and maintain their backend APIs using Rails, MEAN, or LAMP stacks and associated technologies.

PROJECTS

iPHONE APP | Wikable 2017 | Seattle, WA

 Developed a prototype Wikipedia client in Objective C using VoiceOver and DynamicText to make content accessible to people with visual impairment.

iPHONE APP | RouteStats 1 2016 | Seattle, WA

 Developed a small app to display realtime and aggregate travel statistics using Swift, MapKit, CoreLocation, and CloudKit.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

Swift, Objective C, JavaScript, HTML, C++, PERL, Ruby, BASH, MySQL, LATEX

TOOLS & FRAMEWORKS

ReactiveSwift, ReSwift, Moya, Object-Mapper, AlamoFire, Nimble/Quick, XCT-est, CoreData, MapKit, CoreLocation

EDUCATION

HARVEY MUDD COLLEGE Spring 2007 | Claremont, CA BS in Mathematics Thesis: Kolmogorov Complexity of Unlabeled Graphs Coursework with a strong emphasis on computability and algorithmic complexity

CODE FELLOWS

2015 - 2016 | Seattle, WA Advanced iOS Development with Swift and Objective-C Advanced Full-Stack Development with JavaScript